-[water rippling]
-[Saeng-gang grunts]
[panting]
[uneasy music playing]
[music intensifies]
[Saeng-gang grunting]
[grunts loudly]
[panting]
Gu-cheon.
Gu-cheon!
You need to wake up. Come back!
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Are you all right?
Gu-cheon! Gu-cheon!
-[tense music playing]
-[gasps]
[groaning]
[Saeng-gang coughs. gasps]
[Saeng-gang gasping]
[spectral voice exclaiming]
[Saeng-gang coughs. gasps]
[Saeng-gang gasping]
[grunts. gasping]
[coughing]
[music swells]
THE EAST PALACE
So you managed to deal with
the 13 court ladies' spirits
in the salt storehouse.
You did very well. You may leave now.
There is something I must ask.
Did you have anything to do with
the salt storehouse seal getting broken?
You have changed.
seeing that you now have the bravery
to ask such questions.
However. you must've seen by now
the bloodshed that words
other people have said
can unleash within the palace.
Or have you forgotten about your mother?
"I'll dry out the seed
of the East Palace."
Those were the words
of the Most Favored Lady of the Court.
who drowned in the pond 30 years ago.
She is the pond spirit. is she not?
Who was that woman. actually?
And what was the reason for her death?
[mysterious pensive music playing]
Are you the only one who knows of this.
or does Gu-cheon know as well?
I am the only one who knows.
Do not say anything about it to him.
Who was the pond spirit
when she was alive?
I can catch her if you can answer me that.
I am only telling you this one more time.
Stop digging into the pond spirit.
and find a way to catch it
without uncovering its identity.
Cease this incessant prying immediately.
Anyone who tries to uncover
the palace disgrace dies.
Even if they are
a child of the royal lineage.
[Gu-cheon coughing]
[Gu-cheon groans. coughs]
[music fades]
I assume you are not better?
You're recovering much slower than before.
Well. sending 13 spirits
back to the afterlife
took most of my yang energy out of me.
I will never do such an amount again.
[coughs. sniffles]
[Saeng-gang] All right.
Can you explain what happened?
Why did you strangle me back there?
[uneasy music playing]
[melancholy string music playing]
-I strangled you?
-Yes.
It was
like you were almost possessed.
[Gu-cheon sighs]
Down in that world…
I lose a large amount of my yang energy
when I fight.
And when I lose too much yang energy.
I end up in a spirit-like state.
even after coming out of the water.
At times. I lose consciousness briefly.
and I'm unaware of anything at all.
That is why I must leave here
as soon as I'm able to.
And that is the reason
I hate hunting spirits.
Right.
[music fades]
Now that I've revealed to you my secret.
you should tell me…
what's really on your mind right now.
Who is it that you want to kill
while you're here?
[suspenseful music playing]
The person who killed my mother.
-[tense music playing]
-[women groaning in pain]
A cursed object filled with human remains
was found in the salt storehouse.
You gave His Majesty only one princess.
and then. because of that.
you were never seen again.
Out of jealousy. you cursed the Queen
and the rest of the concubines.
did you not?
I am innocent.
[sobs. breathes shakily]
That was not my cursed object.
I swear it's not mine.
[Queen] Enough.
This is your doing.
-[woman 1] Your Majesty.
-[Jang] Keep going.
-[women crying]
-[woman 1] Your Majesty!
[breathing heavily]
[Saeng-gang] Ten years ago.
it was Her Majesty the Queen Dowager
who framed my mother
and forced her out of the palace.
It is Mother. Please help her.
Mother and the court maids are innocent.
Oh. please. Father.
The Queen is hurting Mother.
I know that it is all my fault because
I heard a strange voice. but I promise--
-Enough.
-[gasps]
She will be stripped of her station
for burying a cursed object
and then banished.
That is the only way she will live.
But that cursed object was not Mother's.
It was not. Father.
The spirit in the salt storehouse said.
"The serpent's shed skin--"
-[young Saeng-gang gasps]
-[mysterious music playing]
It's best you hold your tongue.
You must not tell me
that you hear such things.
Not any child that bears my blood.
Unless you wish to bring disgrace
to our name.
Do not tell a single soul any of it.
Do you understand?
How foolish you are.
How utterly foolish.
You need to learn your place.
Now. mind your tongue in the palace.
[breathing shakily]
You and your mother
shall be cast out at once!
But. Father. please…
How could you?
[melancholy music playing]
[Saeng-gang]
After we were cast out of the palace.
Mother was poisoned to death.
All because she uncovered
the cursed object in the salt storehouse
and drew close
to the secret of the pond spirit.
The one who sought to protect
the pond spirit's secret
is the one who killed my innocent mother.
Are you sure you should be saying this?
I need you to be able to unravel
my mother's secret.
That's why I place my trust in you.
[Gu-cheon] Good heavens.
What a life this is. [grunts]
[Gu-cheon moans]
[Gu-cheon] You can leave now.
[sighs]
We need to find the true identity
of the Most Favored Lady of the Court.
Get ready and come out.
[door opens]
[music fades]
I went to pay my respects
at the Queen Dowager's quarters
and saw Saeng-gang walking by.
She was dressed as a court lady
and accompanied by a man.
Have you made her do something dangerous?
You need not concern yourself with it.
Mother.
do you not remember?
You need only attend to my son.
That aside…
the Queen Dowager
is harboring some ulterior motives.
[unsettling music playing]
It seems she intends…
to have Prince Iksang's eldest son named
Crown Prince.
Well. even so.
we must act for the sake of
the Jongmyo Shrine and good fortune altar.
[scoffs. laughs]
Are you saying that even though you know
what I had to endure for this seat.
you still choose to come and tell me
to act for the sake of the shrine?
Things will not unfold
as the Queen Dowager intends them to be.
My son will take the throne.
and I will make sure that it does happen.
It will be his.
Yes.
Even if I do have to conjure spirits.
There.
[music fades]
[window opens]
Why did we sneak
into Lady Jang's quarters?
It's not as if we are thieves.
[sighs]
Are you the sage of morality? Huh?
Lady Jang has spent her entire life
by the Queen Dowager's side.
She must know all of her secrets.
So I'm trying to scare her into spilling
everything about the pond spirit.
Then do it correctly. all right?
And what is that?
[sighs]
[woman 1] Madam.
-You're back earlier than usual.
-[Gu-cheon grunts]
[Jang] I was not feeling myself.
I came back to rest.
[Gu-cheon] Wait! Uh…
[gasps]
-[door rattling]
-[Jang grunts]
Who… Who are you?
Who gave you permission to come in here?
The pond spirit is…
is right here. with you.
Wait. are you not that feng shui man
who recently got here?
-What are you doing in my quarters?
-Sh. Sh.
-Look at these footprints on the floor.
-[Jang gasps]
[Jang] What…
This is not pond mud.
[Jang] Get out of here immediately.
or I'll call someone.
-[Gu-cheon] Hold on!
-I will!
I can feel the pond spirit.
It's close to us.
-[Jang] What?
-[Gu-cheon breathes shakily]
-[purrs]
-[Gu-cheon] The pond spirit is over there.
[Jang] What… What is…
[Gu-cheon] Hey you!
You should earn your keep.
-[Jang] This bastard…
-Do what you do best. Now!
-[Jang] What do you think you are doing?
-Hey! Come on.
[Jang] What are you doing?
Explain yourself.
-[Gu-cheon] Hey.
-How dare you pull such an absurd stunt!
Somebody come in here now!
-[Saeng-gang crying]
-[door rattling]
[Jang] Where is that crying coming from?
I will dry out the seed
of the East Palace.
[sobs]
[Gu-cheon] It's the pond spirit.
The pond spirit has come.
Did I not tell you when I went
to the Queen Dowager's quarters?
A won-gwi seeks out the one
responsible for its death.
[purring]
[ominous music playing]
[Jang whimpering. gasping]
[whimpers]
[music swells]
[spectral scream]
[Jang screaming]
[Jang gasps]
[air whooshing]
[belches]
[purrs]
[Gu-cheon] Homage to Amitabha Buddha.
Homage to Amitabha Buddha.
You said you were a feng shui master?
Do you also know how to deal with spirits?
[Gu-cheon clears throat]
Speaking of which…
The thing is. Lady Jang.
this spirit will come looking for you
again any moment.
It will? [breathes shakily]
What should I do if it does?
[Gu-cheon] In order to keep
the pond spirit from coming in here.
I have to know exactly how it lived
when it was alive.
[Jang breathes nervously]
[Saeng-gang] Do not worry. Lady Jang.
You can tell him everything you know.
He will keep it a secret
from the Queen Dowager.
He's capable of doing that.
[Gu-cheon] What?
Of course.
So. then.
who might that ghost be?
[sighs nervously]
The spirit is…
the late King's
last Most Favored Court Lady.
[tense music playing]
[Jang] A woman of the lowest birth.
nothing more than a menial labor maid.
caught the late King's eye
and received his favor
and even conceived his child.
[men grunting]
[Jang] But it later came to light
that the woman
was in a relationship with a royal guard.
When Her Majesty found out
about that fact…
-[water splashing]
-[grunting]
…she ordered the royal guard
to be tortured.
[soldier] Hold still!
[gasping]
-[Jang] But he did not readily confess.
-[coughs. groans]
[Jang] So soldiers were sent out.
and they uncovered evidence.
-And in the end. he admitted to the crime.
-Search it!
It turned out that the child
was not the late King's at all.
It was the royal guard's.
After enduring torture.
the Most Favored Lady miscarried
and died with resentment
for the royal family burning in her heart.
I will dry out the seed
of the East Palace! [screams]
-[blade slices]
-[women screaming]
[women gasping]
[Gu-cheon] Then what happened to her body?
Do you know?
It was secretly taken out of the palace.
A grave would never have been an option.
And her belongings?
As a traitor to the Crown.
the body was burned.
So there is nothing left of her
besides her memory?
She had no family.
so it was to be expected.
-[music fades]
-[Jang moans]
So the Most Favored Lady of the Court
cursed the royal house
after dying for her own wrongdoing?
Surely that isn't everything.
A hidden palace disgrace lies behind this.
I will have to ask it myself. then.
Is there a way to summon the spirit?
Then what will you do?
There's no way to send it
to the afterlife.
Lady Jang mentioned
that everybody who entered
the royal guard's house
seemed to have met an untimely death.
It appears the royal guard's spirit
has settled himself there.
Exactly.
There's a reason the royal guard died
and remained in that house
instead of moving on.
Since they were lovers.
her belongings may still be there.
We must stop by his house immediately.
Have you lost your mind?
An untimely death is your big plan?
Have you made a plan?
I'm the one who can leave
and come back as I please.
I know of another way I can leave.
If I become a soul.
[mysterious pensive music playing]
Is that even… possible?
It is. but also dangerous.
If the body and soul drift too far apart…
it will be difficult to return.
If I fail.
my soul could lose its way…
and I will become a spirit.
If that happens.
I will surely become an ak-gwi.
And what is that?
An ak-gwi is someone who died
but is burdened with great karma.
In life. you…
[music subsides]
Are you all right?
[unsettling music playing]
[melodic spectral voice singing]
[Saeng-gang] Do you see something
in that well over there?
[mystical ethereal music playing]
You do not look very well.
If you need my yang energy. I could--
If you wanted to give me your yang energy.
then you would have to hold me close
and lend me your warmth.
Can you do that?
Forget it.
I have no intention of doing that either.
So are you going to stay like this?
No. It will only get worse.
Then from now on. I will go with you
to that realm to help you.
Two are better than one.
Teach me how to go there.
Let's be perfectly clear.
You would like me to show you
how to die like me?
I should be spending my days helping you.
There is only one way you could.
Go and tell the King what you know.
Tell him we can't capture
the pond spirit any longer
and that I may lose my mind
and start killing people.
so he must let me go.
That is not possible.
You have to find a way.
And do not naively believe
that he will let you leave the palace.
Then I must choose
to leave here in death after all.
[tense music stinger]
If I die within these walls.
I will return
as an intensely ruthless ak-gwi.
And when I do come back…
the first person I will kill is the King.
I'm sorry.
Are you daring
to threaten His Majesty's life?
Why does it matter to you?
You hate him as much as I do.
Yes. however. he is this country's King.
Those of royal blood are all the same.
They use whoever they please
to get what they want.
and they don't blink
over the death or life of others.
You're just the same as the rest.
[woman] Miss?
[music fades]
Royal Noble Consort Sukbin
wishes to see you.
[Saeng-gang]
It has been a while. Grandmother.
His Majesty told me everything.
How could you think to disguise yourself
as a court lady and enter the gates?
And why are you back
in these walls again. Grandmother?
It was you who hated coming in here
more than anybody.
You will not be answering my question.
will you?
Predisposed to change the subject.
[sighs]
I am exhausted. [chuckles]
-[Sukbin] Oh.
-Goodness gracious.
[Saeng-gang sighs]
Saeng-gang.
I hope you do not get swept up
in palace strife again.
like you did when you were a child.
[Saeng-gang chuckles]
In the end. Grandmother.
only you worry about me.
After Mother and I
were driven out of here forever.
you were the only person
who took care of us.
no matter what went on.
And how is that man?
I have heard that he is strange
and rather dangerous.
He is strange. I must admit.
But he is the one
I need most in this moment.
He can be dangerous as well.
But I do not care. as long as
I do not begin seeking his friendship.
The palace is a place
where the healthy become ill.
[unsettling music playing]
And people with darkness in their hearts
will end as ak-gwi.
So you see. you must take care.
[voice echoes] Gu-cheon.
Gu-cheon?
My baby.
Let me hold you just once.
You have missed me. have you not?
Come here.
[tense sinister music plays]
[music fades]
[woman 1] This is an ill omen.
People have died here before.
That is why the well was sealed.
And now
another menial labor maid has died.
A menial labor maid carrying wash water
walked by the well at dawn
and saw a man was by it.
-[woman 1] Is that so?
-[woman 2] Yes.
The maid said it was the feng shui master
staying at the East Palace.
Shall I turn him over
to the State Tribunal for questioning?
[woman 1] No. The Queen Dowager's
70th birthday banquet is drawing near.
This must be handled discreetly.
We must not make a fuss.
[women] Yes. madam.
[mysterious music playing]
[indistinct chattering]
[ominous music plays]
[unsettling music playing]
[Saeng-gang] Gu-cheon.
[panting]
[gasps]
Explain this bloodstain.
[breathing shakily] What is this?
Explain to me why you were
wandering around at midnight.
Whose blood is this?
What do you mean "whose"?
Are you telling me
that I have hurt someone?
Then it must be your blood.
Where were you hurt? Why were you hurt?
My nose must have bled
after I had nodded off.
After fighting the court ladies.
I lost my strength.
And that Ggeomeoksali
is still draining my yang energy.
I have already told you
that I lose my yang energy
in the other world.
[Saeng-gang sighs]
[door opens. closes]
[breathing shakily]
-[groaning]
-[tense music playing]
[woman] Prince Yeongan.
You must regain your strength.
Prince Yeongan.
It was not this severe before.
Your Majesty.
but his condition suddenly worsened.
[tense music continues]
[King] Coming here.
it brings me back to the days when
I lived in the East Palace as a young boy.
This place still sends chills
down my spine.
[Gu-cheon] So what brings you
to such a dreadful place?
[tense music playing]
How much longer do I have to wait?
I came in person to hear your answer.
[Gu-cheon] First of all.
allow me to leave the palace.
If I stay here any longer.
then all of the palace's yin energy
will kill me.
If you let me leave here.
I will find a way
to capture the pond spirit.
Tomorrow is the Queen Dowager's
70th birthday banquet.
Eliminate the pond spirit
and restore Prince Yeongan.
You will have until noon.
Your Majesty. I just--
Your life means nothing to me.
The day you will leave here
is the day that I no longer draw breath.
If my son cannot walk directly
into the Queen's banquet
on his own two feet tomorrow.
I promise I will kill you
and bind your soul to this palace
for all time.
Do you understand?
[music intensifies]
[music fades]
Wait. Are you not the feng shui man
who has been staying in the East Palace?
Why are you in a place
reserved only for women?
-Where is the owner of these quarters?
-Pardon?
I may be younger than you.
but I am still a court lady.
Watch how you speak to me.
This will not do. You should be helping.
Wait. what? I… I mean… What?
The order came from Miss Saeng-gang.
Hurry.
Uh. oh…
[unsettling music playing]
[Ji-yul] What is he doing?
[blows air]
[Ji-yul gasps] Wait. What are you doing?
[dramatic percussive music playing]
[Ji-yul] What exactly
did Miss Saeng-gang order you to do?
[Gu-cheon] Place this brass basin
near the residence
of the royal guard's house in Jungchon.
Mark my words.
You must not spill this water.
I have no choice
but to become a soul and seek out
the royal guard through my blood.
[grunts]
[thunder rumbling]
[panicked screams]
What is going on?
It looks like some lightning
struck the jujube tree just now.
[Sukbin] This does not bode well.
What calamity is this
on the Queen Dowager's 70th birthday?
Good heavens. What should we do?
[Gu-cheon] Have you heard of
lightning-struck jujube wood?
[grunts] I have not.
At this rate. every peach tree
in the palace will be stripped bare.
That is exactly what I am saying.
This stuff rots away
the moment I cut a spirit with it.
unlike jujube.
Jujube wood.
How's it different?
Since it's a jujube tree
struck by lightning. it's sturdy.
and it sinks in the water as I do.
[panicked screaming]
[Saeng-gang breathing heavily]
[Gu-cheon] It drives away evil spirits.
so it's ideal for striking them down.
[Saeng-gang] Heaven is on our side.
[tense percussive music playing]
[exhales sharply] Gu-cheon.
[Ji-yul] This is exhausting.
[low rumbling]
[ominous music playing]
[heavy breathing]
[blade rasps]
[heavy breathing. squelching]
[growls]
[hissing. squelching]
[guard. distorted voice]
You cannot take it.
I must protect it.
[growls]
[Gu-cheon panting]
[Gu-cheon growling]
[panicked screams]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[guard growling]
[Gu-cheon panting]
[Gu-cheon grunting]
[guard growls]
[grunting]
[guard growling]
[tense dramatic music playing]
[both grunting]
[guard growls]
[music intensifies]
[guard growls. grunts]
[both growl]
[panting]
[music intensifies]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
-[music subsides]
-[Gu-cheon grunts]
[guard snarls]
[panicked screams]
-[tense dramatic music resumes]
-[both grunting]
[music intensifies]
[music swells]
[blades clanking]
[both grunting]
[guard growls]
[panting]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[guard growls]
[both grunting]
[music swells. subsides]
[Saeng-gang breathing heavily]
[both groaning]
[Gu-cheon] Stop it!
[Gu-cheon grunting]
What are you trying to protect.
even in death?
[guard. distorted voice] It's my crime.
I have to return it.
It is
my crime.
I did it.
[guard growls] I did it!
[tense dramatic music playing]
[Saeng-gang] This is the sword
stained with your blood. Take it!
[loud rumbling]
[guard growls]
[dramatic percussive music playing]
-[music subsides]
-[grunts]
-[epic rock music playing]
-[Gu-cheon screams. grunts]
[both grunting. groaning]
[loud groaning]
[guard growls]
[music intensifies]
[music subsides]
[labored breathing]
[exhales sharply]
[Gu-cheon groans]
[panting]
[Gu-cheon grunts]
[guard] I killed her.
After she became the King's woman.
I framed her and
betrayed her as well.
[guard] They said
that if I made a false confession.
the Queen Dowager would at least
spare my family from extermination.
[melancholy music playing]
[guard sighs]
I… buried the baby shirt
that she had made with all her heart.
I buried it beneath this tree.
Therefore.
until she returns. I must protect it here.
I have to.
I must beg for her forgiveness.
[squelching]
[Saeng-gang panting]
[melancholy music intensifies]
[music fades]
[Ji-yul] Huh?
What are you doing?
Miss Saeng-gang! Miss Saeng-gang!
[Ji-yul screams]
-[Ji-yul] No!
-Hey. Gu-cheon. Gu-cheon!
[Ji-yul] Uh. is… is he alive?
This madman went into the other realm
without a tether.
Now I can't pull his soul back.
Come on! Where is your soul being held?
Hey! Gu-cheon!
Are you on your way back?
[Saeng-gang panting]
-[ominous music playing]
-[birds crowing]
[crowing continues]
[spectral voice humming]
[Gu-cheon] If the body and soul
drift too far apart.
it will be difficult to return.
-If I fail. my soul could lose its way.
-Come on! Gu-cheon!
And I will become a spirit.
If that happens.
I will surely become an ak-gwi.
[Saeng-gang] I will not let you
wander the realm as a spirit alone.
I will come and find you. Gu-cheon.
Please wait for me.
Please.
[breathing heavily]
[music swells]
[water burbling]
[melodic ethereal music playing]
[Gu-cheon breathing heavily]
[music intensifies]
[music subsides]
[melodic ethereal music playing]
[breathing heavily]
[echoes] Gu-cheon.
Come to me.
[Gu-cheon moans]
Over here.
Mother.
-[Gu-cheon sighs]
-Gu-cheon!
[tense music playing]
Do not go any closer!
-[mother echoes] Gu-cheon.
-That gwi-mae lures people to their death.
We have to leave this place now.
Follow me out.
-[mother] You missed me. did you not?
-Gu-cheon!
-Please take a closer look!
-[mother] Come on.
[both breathing heavily]
[Sane-gang] Gu-cheon! [gasps]
[Saeng-gang panting]
-[loud thump]
-[grunts]
-[spectral snarling]
-[Saeng-gang panting]
[spectral screaming]
[panting]
[dramatic percussive music playing]
[Saeng-gang grunts. pants]
[Gu-cheon echoes] Mother.
-[muffled gasping]
-[tense eerie music playing]
[Gu-cheon echoes] Mother.
[mother] I died because of you!
[grunts. groans]
[Saeng-gang grunting]
Let go of me!
[creature growls]
[creature snorts]
[creature snarls]
[creature howls]
[groans]
[spectral screams]
[music intensifies]
[spectral screaming]
[pants]
[air whooshing]
[belches]
[purrs]
[squelching]
[snarling]
[growling]
[howling]
[tense dramatic music playing]
[snarls]
[music subsides]
[water splashes]
[pants]
[Saeng-gang] Gu-cheon! [whimpers]
[melancholy ethereal music playing]
[leaves rustling]
[Gu-cheon] Then I must choose
to leave here in death after all.
If I die within these walls.
I will return as
an intensely ruthless ak-gwi.
And when I do come back…
the first person I will kill is the King.
Did he plan…
[breathing heavily]
[music subsides]
[wind whistles]
-[pop instrumental music playing]
-[Gu-cheon pants]
[epic rock music playing]
[music fades]
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm